let's discuss the solution to our tlb
performance quiz we have a one megabyte
array that we are reading one byte at a
time one megabyte is 2 to the 20th bytes
our page is 4 kilobytes
which is 2 to the 12th
so there are 256 pages in this array now
what happens is once you have the first
access you will have a level 1 tlb miss
a level 2 tlb miss and the translation
will be generated and placed in both obs
next when we access the second byte we
have a tlb hit because that byte is in
the same page as the previous one so
after the first miss
we will have
hits for the remainder of the four
kilobyte page in the first sweep we will
have 256
l1
tlb misses because that's how many pages
we accessed and we will have 4095
this is one less than four kilobytes
times 256
tlb hits at level one after this first
sweep
the level one tlb
contains the entries for the second half
of the array because the array needs 256
pages we only have 128 entries
the level 2 tlb however
contains the mappings for the entire
array because it still has enough
elements to hold them so what's going to
happen after the first sweep
is the level one tlb will continue doing
this 256 hits and this many misses each
time we sweep but the level 2 tlb will
start hitting all the time
so what we have
is
10 times 256 misses here
and 10 times
hits here
now the question is
for l2 what do we have we know that we
will have 256 misses
that is because during the first sweep
we have no mappings for any of the 256
pages
after the first sweep
we will have the mapping for all the
pages so we will only have hits but the
question is how many of them
well
note that we only access the level 2
till b if we have a miss in the level 1
tlb so the number of hits here will be
this minus this so for nine sweeps we
will be having these misses go here in
big hits
so this is the answer to this quiz